Sub by Netflix & Ripped by skysoultan ♔ Follow @skysoultan on Instagram ♔
Sub by Netflix & Synced by skysoultan ♔ Follow @skysoultan on Instagram ♔
JUNE 2006, SUMMER OF SEVENTEEN
JUNI 2006 MUSIM PANAS USIA 17 TAHUN
Why do you look so sad?
Kenapa kau sedih?
What about you? Why are you so sad?
Lantas kenapa kau sedih juga?
CHA HEON'S BIRTHDAY
ULANG TAHUN CHA HEON
Heon's birthday is coming up.
Sebentar lagi ulang tahun Heon.
I want to buy him a watch,
Aku ingin beli arloji sebagai hadiah,
but I'm broke.
tapi tak punya uang.
What about you?
Kau?
FIELD DAY
PESTA OLAHRAGA
I want to buy my dad a gift, but I'm short of money.
Aku juga ingin beli hadiah untuk Ayah, tapi kurang uang.
If it's a gift for your dad,
Kalau demi hadiah untuk ayahmu,
I'll chip in.
tentu harus kubantu.
Forget it. That's nowhere near enough.
Lupakan. Itu tidak cukup.
Great. Then, I'll take it. Many a little makes a mickle.
Berarti ini milikku. Sedikit-sedikit lama-lama menjadi bukit.
Many a little makes a little. Give me that.
Tetap saja sedikit. Singkirkan tanganmu!
Guys, breaking news! You won't believe this.
Teman-teman, ada berita eksklusif!
I just overheard the faculty meeting.
Tadi aku menguping rapat guru.
Guess what the first prize is for the field day?
Tebak berapa hadiah juara Pesta Olahraga kali ini?
It's…
Hadiahnya…
-A whopping… -"Whopping"?
- Hadiahnya… - Berapa?
Spit it out.
Lekas bilang!
A 1,500,000-won gift certificate!
Kupon 1.500.000 won!
It's a 1,500,000-won gift certificate!
Katanya, kupon 1.500.000 won!
-Isn't it awesome? -One and a half million?
- Hebat, 'kan? - Satu juta lima ratus?
That's about 50,000 won per person.
Berarti per orang bisa dapat 50.000 won?
Guys, while we're at it,
Teman-teman, omong-omong soal itu,
does anyone want to do the hurdle relay?
siapa yang mau ikut lari estafet?
It consists of 50m hurdles, a sack race,
Lari gawang 50 meter, balap karung,
and eating a hot dog while hula hooping.
dan lomba makan corn dog sambil hulahop.
You have to do all three.
Total tiga cabang.
-Shall we? -Yes.
- Kita ikut? - Ya.
We'll do it.
Kami mau!
-One, two, three. -Let's go!
- Satu, dua, tiga. Ayo! - Ayo!
-Do you want to start practicing today? -Yes.
- Mau mulai berlatih hari ini? - Ya.
Run. Faster.
Lari! Cepat!
Faster.
Cepat lari!
This way.
Lewat sini.
Go faster.
Ayo cepat!
Faster.
Cepat!
I'm sure we'll win first place.
Kita pasti juara satu!
-Right? 1.5 million won is ours. -Ours.
- Ya, 1.500.000 won milik kita! - Milik kita!
Hey, Ha-young. I got you boiled eggs.
Hampir lupa. Ha-young, aku bawa telur.
Eat up. You need a lot of protein before the field day.
Kau harus banyak makan protein sampai hari Pesta Olahraga.
You're making sense for once.
Tumben kau bicara benar.
Here you go.
Silakan.
I'm offering you all the eggs I have.
Kupersembahkan seluruh telur yang kubawa kepadamu.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
If it's okay with you,
Kalau tak keberatan,
may I devote my life to you, too?
boleh kuberikan hidupku juga?
No.
Tidak.
Hey, Sol-i. You're the last runner in the hurdle relay.
Hei, Shin Sol-i! Lari gawang urutan terakhir.
Go for it.
Semangat!
Shin Sol-i.
Shin Sol-i.
The fate of the 1.5 million won is in your hands.
Kau adalah penentu hadiah 1.500.00 won.
Don't worry.
Tak apa, Kawan.
I'll be your coach.
Biar kulatih.
Let's see how good you are first.
Perlihatkan kemampuanmu dahulu.
He's an athlete. He must be good.
Dia atlet. Pasti punya dasar.
THEORY AND PRACTICE OF TRACK AND FIELD HURDLES
TEORI DAN PRAKTIK ATLETIK LARI GAWANG
Heon!
Heon,
I think we were meant to be.
tampaknya kita memang ditakdirkan.
I can't believe we bumped into each other here.
Bahkan kita bertemu di sini. Ya, 'kan?
Heon, I keep knocking over hurdles.
Heon, aku jatuh terus saat lari gawang.
Is it because I can't keep my balance?
Apa karena aku tak bisa menjaga keseimbangan?
By the way,
Omong-omong,
weren't you good at hurdling in middle school?
bukankah kau mahir lari gawang saat SMP?
I won't help you.
Aku tak akan membantu.
You're so cold.
Kau tegas sekali.
What's that book about?
Buku apa itu?
I just picked it.
Aku hanya asal pilih.
HUMAN ANATOMY
ANATOMI MANUSIA
Bye.
Dah.
He just picked it?
Hanya asal pilih?
Did you find the book your coach asked you to find?
Buku yang diminta pelatihmu sudah ketemu?
No. It's not here.
Tidak. Ternyata tak ada.
Let's just go practice.
Mari kita berlatih saja!
Okay.
Baiklah.
Am I taking too much of your training time?
Aku tak mengganggu waktu latihanmu?
No worries. I practiced a lot already.
Jangan khawatir. Aku sudah banyak berlatih.
All right.
Kita mulai, ya?
When you're hurdling, the quicker the jump, the better!
Semakin sedikit waktu melompat gawang, semakin baik!
Lean forward as you run.
Jadi, bungkukkan tubuh sedikit.
Lower your center of gravity.
Rendahkan tumpuanmu saat melompat.
And most importantly…
Lalu yang terpenting…
DON'T LOSE YOUR BALANCE
JANGAN SAMPAI HILANG KESEIMBANGAN!
Don't lose your balance!
Jangan sampai hilang keseimbangan.
Give it a try.
Cobalah!
Are you okay?
Kau tak apa?
You did great.
Kerja bagus.
Good. You're fast.
Bagus! Cepat sekali.
Come on.
Hei! Ya ampun.
That's not how you do it.
Bukan begitu caranya.
What are you doing?
Sedang apa kau?
-Get out. -No.
- Biar kutunjukkan. - Tak perlu.
Watch how I do it and learn.
Lihat aku dan pelajari dengan baik.
-Get out. -What? No, thanks.
- Biar kutunjukkan. - Tak perlu.
Get out.
Biar kuberi tahu.
-No. -Get out. I'll teach you.
- Tidak perlu. - Lepaslah. Biar aku tunjukkan.
Hey, are you okay?
Kau tak apa?
What's your problem?
Apa-apaan kau?
Ha-young, are you okay? Can you walk?
Ha-young, kau tak apa? Bisa jalan?
All I did was pull the bag a little.
Aku hanya mendorong sedikit.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
I'll take her to the nurse's office.
Enyah kau. Biar kubawa dia ke UKS.
Get off me.
Lupakan! Lepas.
-Ha-young, are you okay? -Are you okay?
- Ha-young, kau tak apa? - Kau tak apa?
-One, two, three. -Three.
- Satu, dua, tiga. - Tiga.
How did you get hurt?
Kenapa bisa cedera?
She fell while practicing for the field day and sprained her ankle.
Kakinya terkilir saat sedang berlatih untuk Pesta Olahraga.
Mr. Lee, is Ha-young going to be all right?
Pak, Ha-young tidak apa, 'kan?
Can someone die from spraining their ankle?
Apa ada penyakit mematikan akibat kaki terkilir?
Why are you overreacting?
Jangan berlebihan!
Mr. Lee, I'm really okay,
Pak, aku sungguh tak apa.
and I recover really quickly.
Pemulihanku pun amat cepat.
I'll be perfectly fine in a few days.
Aku pasti pulih setelah beberapa hari.
It's swollen quite a bit. Are you sure?
Kau tak apa meski kakimu bengkak begini?
You have to go to the hospital.
Kau harus segera ke rumah sakit.
You need to wear a splint.
Kurasa kau harus pakai gips
You can't join the race.
dan jangan ikut Pesta Olahraga.
Ask someone else to do it.
Ganti dengan orang lain.
But I have to.
Aku harus ikut.
Ha-young, listen to Mr. Lee.
Benar, turuti kata Pak Guru.
I'll find someone to replace you.
Biar kucarikan pengganti.
I'll wash your hair
Aku bisa mengeramasi rambutmu
and carry your backpack.
dan membawakan tasmu.
I'll be your hands and feet.
Pokoknya, aku bisa jadi tangan dan kakimu.
Do you need anything?
Kau perlu apa?
Stop it, Jin-hwan.
Hentikan, Jeong Jin-hwan.
It doesn't hurt much, though.
Padahal tidak sakit.
SHIN SOL-I
SHIN SOL-I
Heon, what are you doing?
Heon, kau sedang apa?
I'm studying. What's up?
Belajar. Kenapa?
Well, it's nothing important.
Tidak apa-apa.
Come to think of it, because of the hurdle practice,
Dipikir-pikir, kita sudah lama tak pulang bersama
we haven't biked home together in a while.
sebab aku selalu berlatih lari gawang.
You're talking as if we do that every day.
Memang kita selalu pulang bersama?
We still bike home together quite often.
Kita cukup sering pulang bersama.
Heon, how about we we meet at the playground briefly?
Heon, bisa kita bertemu sebentar di taman depan rumah?
Now?
Sekarang?
But I'm studying right now.
Aku sedang belajar.
I have something to tell you.
Padahal aku ingin bercerita.
Say it over the phone.
Lewat telepon saja.
Well, Ha-young hurt her leg today.
Aku hanya ingin bercerita kalau mendadak Ha-young terkilir tadi.
It's because Se-hyeong suddenly pulled a prank.
Semua gara-gara Wang Se-hyeong bercanda.
So the school nurse said she might not be able to do the race.
Jadi, kata Guru UKS, dia mungkin tak bisa ikut Pesta Olahraga.
But you don't need to worry.
Tapi kau tak perlu khawatir.
It's not serious. She'll get better with a little rest.
Cederanya tak parah. Cukup istirahat beberapa hari.
-Okay. -Oh, right!
- Begitu rupanya. - Aku baru ingat!
Something really funny happened.
Ada cerita lucu lagi.
Jin-hwan tried to lift Ha-young up.
Tadinya Jin-hwan mau menggendong Ha-young,
But he couldn't. He struggled so hard.
tapi dia gagal karena terlalu berat.
Isn't it so funny?
Lucu sekali, 'kan?
Heon, are you listening?
Heon, kau dengar aku?
-Yes. -Okay.
- Ya. - Begitu, ya?
Anyway, we need to find a replacement for Ha-young.
Pokoknya, Ha-young harus digantikan.
It's too bad, isn't it?
Sayang sekali, ya?
Jeez.
Aduh.
Do you know why she's practicing so hard?
Kau tahu kenapa dia berusaha begitu keras?
She wants to buy
Dia ingin beli kado ulang tahun
a birthday present for someone.
dengan kupon hadiah juara.
Heon!
Heon!
Dae-sung, you should teach her again. She can't jump a single one.
Woo Dae-sung, coba kau latih dia lagi. Dia gagal terus.
I tried my best.
Sudah kulatih, tapi tak berhasil.
Ha-young. Don't be bothered.
Jangan khawatir, Ha-young.
Sol-i doesn't have the right build to begin with.
Sol-i sudah kalah secara fisik.
Jin-hwan, you're too hard on her.
Jin-hwan, bicaramu soal kawanku sudah keterlaluan.
He's right. Cheer for her.
Benar. Lekas semangati Sol-i!
Let's go, Shin Sol-i!
Semangat, Shin Sol-i!
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
Dae-sung. Move aside. I'm tired.
Menyingkirlah, Dae-sung. Aku lelah.
Your posture is completely wrong.
Postur tubuhmu salah.
What?
Apa?
Heon, will you help me?
Heon, kau mau membantuku?
I saw the other girls, and it looked like none of them could hurdle right.
Tadi kulihat tak satu pun siswi bisa melompati gawang.
Your short legs aren't to blame, so don't worry.
Jadi, tenang saja. Itu bukan karena kau pendek.
Are you here to insult me?
Kau berniat menyinggungku?
Will you practice or not?
Lantas kau mau lanjut atau tidak?
I will!
Lanjut!
Your records don't look good.
Catatan waktumu buruk.
I hear you spend more time on the running track than you do in the pool.
Kata murid lain, kau lebih sering ada di lapangan ketimbang di kolam renang.
-The field day is next week-- -Which has nothing to do with you.
- Pekan depan ada Pesta Olahraga. - Apa urusannya denganmu?
Does it include swimming?
Adakah perlombaan renang di sana?
Focus on the swim meet.
Fokuslah berlatih untuk pertandingan.
DON'T LOSE YOUR BALANCE
JANGAN SAMPAI HILANG KESEIMBANGAN!
YUIL HIGH SCHOOL ONE MIND FIELD DAY
PESTA OLAHRAGA KEBERSAMAAN SMA YUIL
CLASS 1-4
KELAS 1-4
-We can do it!
- Kita pasti bisa!
-Let's go, Class 1-6!
- Semangat, Kelas 1-6!
-Go for it! -Do or die!
- Semangat! - Kita harus menang.
-Class seven is the best
- Kelas 1-7 yang terbaik!
-Class seven, win it all
- Menanglah Kelas 1-7!
-Class seven, go!
- Kelas 1-7, semangat!
Class seven, you're awesome!
Kelas 1-7 keren!
Ladies and gentlemen.
Selamat siang.
The freshwomen's hurdle relay will begin shortly.
Sesaat lagi lomba lari estafet putri kelas satu segera dimulai.
-Are you ready? -All runners,
- Kau siap? - Semua pelari
-Take a deep breath. -please gather round.
- Tarik napas dalam. - dimohon berkumpul.
-Mi-nyeo, good luck. -Thanks.
- Mi-nyeo, kau juga semangat! - Ya.
-Su-jin. -Yes?
- Su-jin. - Ya?
-Good luck. -Thanks.
- Kau juga semangat! - Semangat!
Let's go.
Semangat!
Yes?
Ada apa?
Don't be nervous.
Tak perlu gugup.
CLASS 1-7
KELAS 1-7
Ready.
Bersiap!
DAZZLING CLASS SEVEN
KELAS 1-7 BERSINAR
Let's go.
Ayo maju!
Go!
Semangat!
-Run! -Faster!
- Lari! - Lebih kencang!
Class six, run!
Kelas 1-6, lari!
-Class seven!
- Kelas 1-7!
Take this!
Seok-min!
-Faster! -Let's go!
- Cepat, Su-jin! - Ayo!
Mi-nyeo, take it.
Mi-nyeo, ambil ini!
Mi-nyeo, take it!
Mi-nyeo, ambil!
Go!
Ayo!
Mi-nyeo, run!
Lari, Mi-nyeo!
Why is she so fast?
Kenapa kau cepat sekali?
-Go! -Quickly!
- Semangat! - Mi-nyeo!
-Mi-nyeo, hurry up! -Go!
- Hei!
-Hey! -What are you doing? Stop eating!
- Sedang apa kau? Berhenti makan!
Mi-nyeo!
Mi-nyeo!
Here. These are all yours.
Ini. Semuanya milikmu.
Come on. Quickly.
Cepat kemari!
These are all yours. Faster.
Semua milikmu. Cepat!
-Good job! -Yes!
- Bagus! - Ya!
Mi-nyeo, hurry up!
Cepat, Mi-nyeo!
Good job!
Bagus!
-Sol-i, let's go! -Go for it!
- Shin Sol-i, semangat! - Sol-i, semangat!
-Shin Sol-i!
- Shin Sol-i!
She's winning!
Sol-i!
DAZZLING CLASS SEVEN
KELAS 1-7 BERSINAR
Thank you, Teddy Bear.
Terima kasih, Beruang!
-Heon! -Shin Sol-i!
- Heon! - Shin Sol-i!
-Was I good?
- Hebat, 'kan?
Dae-sung, thanks so much.
Terima kasih banyak, Dae-sung.
I can't believe I had to go at the important moment.
Kenapa aku selalu sakit perut di saat-saat penting, ya?
Thank you so much.
Terima kasih banyak.
No problem. I had fun.
Tak apa. Ini menyenangkan.
Man, you're sweating a lot.
Panas, ya? Keringatmu banyak.
It was really hot.
Ya, agak panas.
I bet.
Ya, 'kan?
GIFT CERTIFICATE
KUPON HADIAH
Jeez, Se-hyeong.
Yang benar saja, Se-hyeong!
I thought it was 1.5 million won, but turns out it's 150,000 won.
Waktu itu kukira 1.500.000 won. Ternyata 150.000 won.
How many zeros were there?
Nolnya ada berapa, ya?
I can't buy anything with this.
Ini tidak cukup.
Anyway,
Entahlah. Lupakan.
I have to go see my dad now.
Aku harus pergi menemui Ayah.
Now? Why? You'll get caught at the gate.
Sekarang? Kenapa mendadak? Kau pasti tertahan di gerbang.
But I have to go now. I'm already late.
Aku harus pergi. Aku sudah terlambat.
Actually, my dad is
Sebenarnya ayahku…
departing today. I won't be able to see him for a few months.
ke luar negeri hari ini. Dia baru bisa ditemui beberapa bulan lagi.
Then you should hurry.
Kau harus bergegas!
-Is there any way? -Jump over the gate.
- Tak ada cara lain? - Bisa lewat pagar.
The one behind the nurse's office.
Pagar belakang Ruang UKS.
Go. Ha-young, you can do it.
Injak saja, Ha-young. Kau pasti bisa.
Hey, what are you doing?
Hei! Kalian sedang apa?
Hurry.
Cepat!
The dean's coming. Ha-young, hurry.
Ada Penertib. Lekas, Ha-young!
What are you doing?
Dae-sung?
How dare you touch my Ha-young?
Beraninya kau menyentuh Ha-young!
Then what? Do you want her to get caught?
Lantas kau ingin dia tertangkap?
Hey, what are you doing over there?
Hei, anak-anak nakal! Kalian sedang apa di sana?
Spread out now.
Lekas menyebar!
You rascals!
Dasar berandalan!
What do you think you're doing?
Hei! Sedang apa kalian?
Stop right there. What are you doing?
Berhenti kalian!
Step aside.
Menyingkir!
Wait, sir. There's a dog!
Pak Guru, ada anjing.
Help me.
Tolong bantu aku.
I'm scared of dogs.
Aku takut anjing.
-Please. -What?
- Kumohon. - Apa?
Where?
Mana?
What?
Anjing siapa itu?
Go away.
Pergi kau!
Go on.
Hei, pergi!
Hey!
Lepaskan!
YUIL HIGH SCHOOL
SMA YUIL
What for?
Apa ini?
Your pants are ripped.
Celanamu sobek.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
-I'm not off to-- -You won't do anything bad, right?
- Aku… - Bukan pergi melakukan hal buruk, 'kan?
Yes. What?
Ya. Apa?
What? No.
Ya, bukan.
Don't get caught.
Jangan sampai ketahuan.
Sub by Netflix & Ripped by skysoultan ♔ Follow @skysoultan on Instagram ♔
Sub by Netflix & Synced by skysoultan ♔ Follow @skysoultan on Instagram ♔
-You really won't do it? -No.
- Sungguh tak mau? - Tidak.
You're a member of Class Seven, too.
Kau juga Kelas 1-7, 'kan?
Everyone will be wearing one. You should too.
Semua teman sekelas pakai ini. Masa kau tidak?
Look, Heon!
Heon!
Thinking about hurdling makes me so nervous.
Aku gugup setengah mati setiap ingat lari gawang.
Happy?
Puas?
Yes, I'm happy.
Puas.
It's good.
Bagus sekali.
You look handsome.
Kau tampan.
-"Let's go, baby." -I'm not a baby.
- "Ayo, Sayang!" - Aku bukan sayangmu.
"That man is mine. He is my boyfriend."
"Pria itu milikku. Pria itu kekasihku."
Why can't you say that?
Kenapa tak bisa bicara begitu?
-Can I love you?
- Apa kuboleh mencintainya?
-Will you? -I'll think about it.
- Kau mau peran ini? - Biar kupertimbangkan.
The male lead is already taken.
Peran utama pria sudah ada.
-Who is it? -Can't you take a hint?
- Siapa? - Dasar tak peka.
"Sir! Can't you see my baby's scared?"
"Pak! Tak lihat sayangku kaget?"
Thanks. Every day is exciting.
Terima kasih. Setiap hari menyenangkan.
You're the best, Brother.
Kau terbaik, Kawan!
No. Don't do it.
Tidak! Jangan.
-Have you seen Sol-i? -Heon.
- Kau lihat Shin Sol-i? - Heon.
Shin Sol-i.
Shin Sol-i.
Subtitle translation by: Soo-hyun Yang
Terjemahan subtitle oleh Listya Ayunita Wardadie